An Inventory to the Pardee Lowe papers, 1911-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
- Soochow University correspondence and printed material, 1950s-1980s. (Box 458)
  Includes miscellaneous correspondence, 1934 and 1947
- Schering company files, 1946-1947 (Box 459)
- Chinese Management Association flyers and clippings, 1947, undated (Box 459)
- American Bureau for Medical Aid to China correspondence, printed material, and clippings, 1940-1942 (Box 459)
- USIS files, 1960s. (Box 459)
  Related to the Summer Institute in Chinese Civilization, Tunghai University, Taichung, Taiwan
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1946 (Box 459)
- Clippings, 1940s-1960s (Box 459)
- Pamphlets bound by Lowe, related to Soviet economics, 1938-1962, and Economics in Taiwan, 1953-1960 (Box 460)
- Harvard Business School notes, 1932 (Box 460)
- Subject files, mainly consisting of clippings, 1950s-1960s (Box 460)
- Pamphlets and reports related to Taiwan and Communist China, bound by Lowe, 1950s-1960s (Box 461-462.)
- Communist China reports, 1951-1958 (Box 463)
- USEF China files, 1960s (Box 463-464.)
- USIA files, 1950s-1960s (Box 463-464.)
- USEF China files, 1950s-1960s (Box 465)
- USIA clippings and printed materials, 1950s (Box 465)
- Department of State and CIA application materials, 1950s (Box 465)
- USIA files, 1950s-1960s. (Box 466)
  Includes personnel file material related to Lowe and to others
- Personal correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 466)
- "Documentary Report on Activities of Pardee Lowe, 1936-1940, with Special Reference to 1937," typescript, submitted to USIA, 1955 July 9 (Box 467)
- USEF China files, 1947-1948 (Box 467)
- Stanford University coursework, 1928 (Box 467)
- Clippings, 1930s-1950s (bulk 1950s) (Box 467-468.)
- USAF Intelligence training materials, 1944-1953 (Box 468)
- USAFR training materials, 1950s (Box 468)
- Clippings files, 1930s-1960s (Box 469-471.)
- Wang Ching-wei subject file, 1939-1940 (Box 469-471.)
- PhD coursework (Box 469-471.)
- GGIE files, 1938-1939 (Box 472-473.)
  - Miguel Covarrubias correspondence (Box 472-473.)
  - Correspondence and printed materials related to reprinting the Miguel Corrubias maps of the peoples of the Pacific and managing their sales in China, 1946-1947 (Box 472-473.)
  - Planning files related to the Department of the Pacific Area, Pacific House, and to China Day at the GGIE (1939 October 29) (Box 472-473.)
  - GGIE printed material, 1939 (Box 472-473.)
  - Panama-Pacific International Exposition, printed material, 1915 (Box 472-473.)
  - Worlds Fairs printed material, 1960s (Box 472-473.)
- China-Burma-India Veterans Association files and clippings, 1950s (Box 472-473.)
- A Short History of the Chinese Communist Party (unidentified translator),compiled and written by Miao Ch'u-huang, original Chinese-language version published by Hsueh His Magazine Press, Peking, 1956 (Box 472-473.)
- Souvenir Views of the Panama-Pacific International Exposition, Pacific Novelty Company of San Francisco, 1915 (Box 474)
- WPA and Emergency Relief Administration subject file, 1930s. (Box 474-475.)
  Consists of notes, 1935, undated; and clippings, 1930s (bulk 1935) See also box 458
- Stanford undergraduate course notes, 1926-1929 (Box 474-475.)
- Clippings, 1950s-1960s (bulk 1960s) (Box 474-475.)
- USAFR training files, 1950s (Box 476)
- Clippings, 1950s-1960s (Box 476)
- Clippings related to France and disarmament, 1920s-1931 (Box 476)
- Schering Company files, 1946-1948 (Box 476)
- GGIE files, 1930s (Box 477)
  - Administrative files (Box 477)
  - Subject files of clippings created to support exhibition planning, 1930s (Box 477)
  - Printed material related to the opening of the San Francisco-Oakland Bay Bridge and the Golden Gate Bridge, 1936-1937 (Box 477)
  - Clippings and photographic souvenirs related to the GGIE (Box 477)
- USAFR training and personnel files, 1950s (Box 477)
- GGIE files, 1930s (Box 478)
- PhD coursework and dissertation research subject files, 1950s (Box 478)
- PhD coursework and dissertation research subject files, 1950s (Box 479-481.)
- Board of Foreign Scholarships meeting agendas and reports, 1949 (Box 479-481.)
  related to USEF China (Fulbright program)
- Clippings, 1960 (Box 479-481.)
- PhD coursework and dissertation research subject files, 1950s. (Box 482)
  Includes clippings, 1950s, especially related to the Cold War
- Subject files related to the Cold War, mainly consisting of clippings, 1950s (Box 483)
- Clippings related to memoirs of President Truman, 1950s (Box 483)
- Phi Lambda U.S.A Charitable Trust files, 1972, 1977-1979, and 1984-1985. (Box 483)
  Includes documents related to proposal for charitable trust to establish and support a two-month study program in Taiwan for Asian-American teenagers
- Father and Glorious Descendant draft writings, undated. (Box 483)
  Organized by chapter
- Creative writing files, 1927-1940s (bulk 1938-1939) (Box 484)
  - "A Man of Humility,", 1940 (Box 484)
  - "China's Three Anti-Japanese Musketeers,", 1938 (Box 484)
  - "The Ideal Church,", 1940 (Box 484)
  - "Inside San Francisco's World's Fair,", 1939. (Box 484)
    Includes photo
  - "Japanese Political Puppetry in North China,", 1938 (Box 484)
  - "The Japanese Terror in Tientsin,", 1939 (Box 484)
    Includes clippings, 1933-1939, undated
  - "Japan's Pan-Asia Doctrine,", undated. (Box 484)
    Consists mainly of clippings, 1938-1939
  - "The KRA Canal-Japan's Answer to Britain's Singapore?", 1938 (Box 484)
  - Kuomintang clippings, 1927 and 1938 (Box 484)
  - "Letters of an Unworthy Younger Brother; Of Letters of Hawk Sung who Respectfully Bows: A Translation by Pardee Lowe,", 1938 (Box 484)
  - Literacy agency correspondence, 1937 (Box 484)
    Related to Lowe acting as literary agent on behalf of other writers
  - Father and Glorious Descendant draft writings, undated. Organized by chapter, with some correspondence related to first publication of the chapters as articles (Box 484)
- Creative writing files, 1930s-1940s, 1972-1973 (bulk 1930s-1940s) (Box 485)
  - Correspondence with Little Brown and Co, mainly related to promotion of Father and Glorious Descendant, 1942-1943 (Box 485)
  - Correspondence with publishers, 1936-1939, 1973 (Box 485)
  - "It's Cocktail Time in Chinatown,", 1938 (Box 485)
  - "Tree-Sitting in Chinatown," typescript, 1936 (Box 485)
  - E. Weil's review of LaPiere's Son of Han, Asia Magazine, 1937 April (Box 485)
  - Father Richard Arens, Fu Jen University, "Reflections on Taiwan's Educational Policy,", 1973 (Box 485)
    Including 1972 manuscript
  - "The Agony of Wei Cheng,", 1949 and undated (Box 485)
  - Correspondence with Little Brown and Co, 1948 and 1973 (Box 485)
  - Correspondence seeking screen version of Father and Glorious Descendant, 1946-1947 (Box 485)
  - "China Fights On," 1938-1939 and typescript review of LaPiere's Son of Han, 1937 (Box 485)
  - Correspondence with Little Brown and Co, 1942-1945 (Box 485)
  - Father and Glorious Descendant draft writings, undated. (Box 485)
  - "Angel of Death-U.S." / "Chungking Terror,", undated and 1940-1941. (Box 485)
  - Topics for composition into articles, notes and clippings, 1937-1939 (Box 485)
- USEFC expenditure records, 1947-1949 (Box 486)
- U.S. military service files, 1942 (Box 486)
- World War II diaries and training notes, 1942-1946, undated (Box 486)
- Printed material, 1943 (Box 486)
- K. C. Li newsletters, 1940-1942. (Box 486)
  Consists of typescript copies of newsletters by Li in the form of letters from Li in the U.S. to Madame Chiang Kai-shek. See also box 334
- Central Intelligence Agency subject file, 1940s-1975. (Box 486)
  Includes draft writings, 1940 and undated
- U.S. Air Force, U.S. Air Force Reserves, and Industrial College of the Armed Forces training course materials, 1950s (Box 487)
- U.S. War Department, China-Burma-India Theater, Shanghai and area, Nanking, and Yunnan, large-format maps, 1940s (Box 488)
- "Moslem Leaders in Communist China Disrobed and Put to Labor,", 1958 December 9 (Box 488)
- "A Personal Account of Life in Canton,", 1958 December 11 (Box 488)
- A Short History of the Chinese Communist Party (unidentified translator), compiled and written by Miao Ch'u-huang, original Chinese-language version published by Hsueh His Magazine Press, Peking, 1956 (Box 488)
- Report on Progress of the Works Program, Works Progress Administration, 1936 October 15 (Box 488)
- GGIE commemorative publications, 1939 (Box 488)
- World's Fair, New York, commemorative publications, 1939 (Box 488)
- New York Times color supplement for Expo '70, Osaka, Japan (Box 488)
- Suydam, E. H., prints of illustrations for Dobie, Charles Caldwell, San Francisco's Chinatown, New York: Appleton-Century Company, 1936 (Box 488)
- GGIE files, 1939 (Box 489)
  Consists of commemorative issues of San Francisco newspaper coverage of GGIE and New York newspaper coverage of the World's Fair, 1939Some issues in full color
- Liu, album of paintings, undated. (Box 489)
  Presented to Lowe in Taiwan by the painter